lurnq.com 2015-02-28

# LurnQ : "Personal Learning Assistant" - PRIVACY POLICY

Technium Labs Private Limited (“Technium Labs”) provides this Privacy Policy to inform you of our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of the information that we collect and receive from users of our services at [ www.LurnQ.com ](http://www.lurnq.com/) (the "Services"). This Privacy Policy applies only to information that you provide to us for the purposes of using the Services. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms of Service (the "Terms"). As used in this policy, the terms 'using' and 'processing' information include using cookies on a computer, subjecting the information to statistical or other analysis and using or handling information in any way, including, but not limited to collecting, storing, evaluating, modifying, deleting, using, combining, disclosing and transferring information within our organization or among our affiliates within India or internationally. 

To utilize the Services available, our registered users identify themselves to the site and we may display personal information to service providers as needed for the provision of the Services. Technium Labs cares deeply about online privacy. If you have any questions concerning this privacy policy, please email us at [team@lurnq.com](mailto:team@lurnq.com). 

WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT

The types of information that [ www.LurnQ.com ](http://www.lurnq.com/) collects fall under two general categories: personally-identifiable-information (PII) and non-personally-identifiable information (non-PII). PII consists of any information which can be used to specifically identify you as an individual. Non-PII consists of aggregate information or any information that does not reveal your identity. 

[ www.LurnQ.com ](http://www.lurnq.com/) collects user submitted information such as name, email address, age to authenticate users and to send notifications to those users relating to the [ www.LurnQ.com ](http://www.lurnq.com/) Service. [ www.LurnQ.com ](http://www.lurnq.com/) also collects other profile data including but not limited to: personal interests, gender, age, education etc., in order to provide the optimum Services. 

When you visit our web sites, you might be providing statistics collected as you browse and personal information you knowingly give us. Be assured that safeguarding the contents of information related to you is our priority. 

We use your personal information to: 

  1. help us provide personalized features 
  2. tailor our sites to your interest 
  3. to get in touch with you when necessary 
  4. to provide the services requested by you 
  5. to preserve social history as governed by existing law or policy 

[ www.LurnQ.com ](http://www.lurnq.com/) also logs non-PII including IP address, profile information, aggregate user data, and information your browser sends, from users and visitors to the site. This data is used to manage the website, track usage and improve the website Services. User IP addresses and/or mobile location may be recorded for security and monitoring purposes.

The following sections describe how your PII and non-PII are collected by us, and how we use such information. 

HOW WE COLLECT AND USE INFORMATION 

Log Files

Any time you visit the site, our servers automatically gather information from your browser (such as your IP addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks). This information may be used to analyze trends, administer the site, prevent fraud, track visitor movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information. We do not share this information externally. 

Cookies

We use "cookies" to keep track of some types of information while you are visiting the Site or using the Service. Cookies are very small files placed on your computer, and they allow us to count the number of visitors to our website and distinguish repeated users from new users. They also allow us to save user preferences and track user trends.  We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information (PII) you submit while on our site, and any cookies used by us would not enable us to view, store or disseminate any PII relating to the user.  You may be able to configure your browser to accept or reject all or some cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences -- however, you must enable cookies from [ www.LurnQ.com ](http://www.lurnq.com/) in order to use most functions on the site. We rely on cookies for the proper operation of our website; therefore if your browser is set to reject all cookies, the site will not function properly. Users who refuse cookies assume all responsibility for any resulting loss of functionality, and shall not at any later point in time, hold us responsible for any such resultant loss in functionality. 

Web Beacons

"Web beacons" (also known as "clear gifs" and "pixel tags") are small transparent graphic images that are often used in conjunction with cookies in order to further personalize our website for our users and to collect a limited set of information about our users. We may also use web beacons in email communications in order to understand the behavior of our users. 

Information About You

When you register for the Service, we collect a variety of information about you to complete your online profile. Except as otherwise stated in this privacy policy, we do not disclose your PII to other users of the Service. 

E-mail

We require an email address from you when you register for the Services. The email messages we send you may contain code that enables our database to track your usage of the emails, including whether the email was opened and what links (if any) were clicked. If you would rather not receive promotional emails from us, please see the section below labeled "Choice/Opt-Out". We reserve the right to send you certain communications, such as service announcements and administrative messages, without offering you the opportunity to opt out of receiving them. We may also contact you by text message (including to any wireless number you may provide to us) solely in connection with the Services.  

Logging onto the website

Log in to the website would be undertaken by the User using his user name and password. 

Demographic Data

Demographic data is also collected at the Site. We use this data to tailor our users’ experience, showing them content that we think they might be interested in, and displaying the content according to their preferences. Some of this information may be shared with advertisers on a non-personally identifiable basis. 

Blogs, Bulletin Boards, Buzz and Public Forums

We make discussion areas of the website available to our users. Any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and that can be used to send you unsolicited communications. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose any PII in these areas. Please consult the Terms of Use and other guidelines available on our website when disclosing any such PII. 

GEOGRAPHICAL LOCATION 

The information that we collect about you may also include your geographical co-ordinates at any particular point in time, tracked in the event that you use our mobile application (or otherwise). By using our services, whether as a registered user or otherwise, you consent unconditionally to our decision to collect and use such information, as also to use of such information to determine or display your exact geographical location at any point in time. 

LINKS 

[ www.LurnQ.com ](http://www.lurnq.com/) contains links to other sites.  The fact that we link to another third party website is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party in any way whatsoever.  Technium Labs  does not exercise control over third party websites and we are not in any way responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices on other sites.  These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personally identifiable information from you, and may use this information for various purposes. Other sites follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personally identifiable information you submit to them. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit.  Our privacy policy only governs information collected on [ www.LurnQ.com ](http://www.lurnq.com/). We shall not be liable in any manner whatsoever for any use (whether authorized or otherwise) of any PII that may be collected by such third parties. 

 ADVERTISING 

Ads appearing on our website may be delivered to users by one or more of our web advertising partners. Our web advertising partners may employ cookies and web beacons to allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad servers may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. 

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies and web beacons by Technium Labs  and does not cover the use of cookies or web beacons by any advertisers. We shall not be liable in any manner whatsoever for any use (whether authorized or otherwise) of any PII that may be collected by such advertisers.

Security   

[ www.LurnQ.com ](http://www.lurnq.com/) is very concerned about safeguarding the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information. [ www.LurnQ.com ](http://www.lurnq.com/)user accounts are secured by user-created passwords. [ www.LurnQ.com ](http://www.lurnq.com/)takes precautions to ensure that user account information is kept private. We employ administrative, physical and electronic measures designed to protect your information from unauthorized access.  If Technium Labs learns of a security systems breach, we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you may take appropriate steps. However, please note that we cannot guarantee the security of user account information. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of user information at any time, and you agree and undertake that we shall not be held liable for any such breach of security of user information.  

We may also use a user's email address to send updates, a newsletter or news regarding the Services. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such information or communications from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications that we send you. 

SHARING AND DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION COLLECTED BY TECHNIUM LABS  

Disclosure by law

Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, Technium Labs will not disclose personal information to any third party unless we believe that disclosure is necessary: 

(1) to conform to legal requirements or to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other legal process received by Technium Labs, whether or not a response is required by applicable law; Technium Labs cooperates with government and law enforcement officials or private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We may disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims, legal process (including subpoenas), to protect the property and rights of Technium Labs or a third party, the safety of the public or any person, to prevent or stop any illegal, unethical, or legally actionable activity, or to comply with the law. Further, any such information may be required to be disclosed pursuant to an administrative or regulatory order, and in such cases, we reserve the right to freely disclose any user information that may be mandated under such regulatory or administrative order.

(2) to enforce the  Terms of Use or to protect our rights in any manner; or 

(3) to protect the safety of members of the public and users of the service. Technium Labs reserves the right to transfer personal information to a successor in interest that acquires rights to that information as a result of the sale of Technium Labs or substantially all of its assets to that successor in interest.  For more information see the "Changes in Our Privacy Policy" section below. 

Disclosure to Trusted Third Parties

We may engage certain trusted third parties to perform functions and provide services to us, including, without limitation, hosting and maintenance, customer relationship, database storage and management, and direct marketing campaigns. 

We may share your non-PII with third parties, but not in a manner that would reveal your identity. We may share your PII, sometimes in conjunction with your non-PII, with service providers that may be associated with us to perform functions on our behalf. For example, outsourced customer support agents or technology infrastructure providers may need access to your information to perform services for you. Your information will be treated as private and confidential by such service providers and not used for any other purpose than we authorize.. If you do not wish to receive offers from our trusted partners, you can change your email preferences at any time by following the steps outlined in the "Choice/Opt-Out" section below. 

Information Transferred As a Result of Sale of Business

As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets and, depending on the transaction, your PII may be one of the transferred assets. In the event that we are acquired by another company, your PII may be part of the assets transferred to the acquiring party. If this occurs, you will be notified if there are any material changes to the way your PII is collected or used. You further hereby agree to the transfer of any PII or other information in relation to you to any such acquirer company as part of the assets transferred to such company.

CHOICE/OPT-OUT 

Registered users who no longer wish to receive updates or notifications may choose not to by selecting the appropriate options in the user profile 'Account Settings'. All notification emails and Technium Labs newsletters also include the above instructions for opting-out of those communications in the future. 

UPDATING YOUR INFORMATION 

You may change your email address, password and other information from the "Account Settings" page accessible via a link from the website home page. To the extent you choose to include PII or other information in your profile, the Services allow you to update or remove that information by editing or deleting the content. 

CHANGES IN PRIVACY POLICY 

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time for any reason; each version will apply to information collected while it was in place. We may not always be able to notify you of any material changes to our Privacy Policy by posting the new Privacy Policy on the Services, and it is your responsibility, as the User, to consult this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes. By continuing to access or use the Services after a modification becomes effective, you agree to be bound by the revised Privacy Policy. If the modified Privacy Policy is not acceptable to you, your only recourse is to cease using the Services. 

HOW CAN YOU CORRECT INACCURACIES IN THE INFORMATION

To correct or update any information you have provided, our sites allow you to do it online. 

DISPUTES

Any dispute, controversy or claim directly or indirectly caused by, arising out of or relating to this Policy will be governed by the laws of India and will be referred to confidential, mandatory and binding arbitration in Bangalore, India.  The arbitration will be conducted on an expedited basis before a single arbitrator appointed by Technium Labs in accordance with the provisions of the Indian Arbitration and Conciliation Act, 1996.  The arbitrator's award shall be substantiated in writing and will be final and binding on you. Subject to the above, you agree to submit yourself to the exclusive jurisdiction of the Courts in Bangalore, India.  

FEEDBACK

If you wish to correct, update or otherwise modify the information that you have provided to us please visit the Profile section on our website and correct, update or modify the relevant information.

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site or your dealings with this Web site, please e-mail [team@lurnq.com](mailto:team@lurnq.com)
